Guide to the Baugh and Sons Company photographs and advertisements, 1905-1932
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Baugh and Sons Company photographs and advertisements 1905-1932
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Baugh and Sons Company (Philadelphia, Pa.)
0.5 linear feet Extent: 101 Items
Producers and distributors of phosphate fertilizer and agricultural chemicals, based in Philadelphia, and Norfolk, Va. Collection includes photographs and advertisements of the Baugh and Sons Company, a chemical distributor associated with Baugh Chemical Company of Baltimore. Topics include offices, factories, products, personnel, and crops. Farm scenes are from New Jersey, Pennsylvania, and North Carolina.
RL.00091
Language: Material inEnglish
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Baugh and Sons Company photographs and advertisements were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift.
Biographical Note
Producers and distributors of phosphate fertilizer and agricultural chemicals, based in Philadelphia, and Norfolk, Va.
Collection Overview
Photographs and advertisements of the Baugh and Sons Company, a chemical distributor associated with Baugh Chemical Company of Baltimore. Topics include offices, factories, products, personnel, and crops. Farm scenes are from New Jersey, Pennsylvania, and North Carolina.
Collection Arrangement
Photographs are arranged by image number assigned by the company, followed by unnumbered and oversize photographs.
Subject Headings
Baugh Chemical Company (Baltimore, Md.); Agricultural chemicals industry -- United States; Fertilizer industry -- United States; Advertising -- Agriculture; Agriculture -- North Carolina; Agriculture -- New Jersey; Agriculture -- Pennsylvania; Agriculture -- United States; Industries -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia
Contents of Collection
- Photographs and Advertisements, 1905-1932, (1 box, 1 oversize folder)
  - Numbered Photographs
    - Asparagus field, 2A (Box 1)
    - Benjamin Harris Brewster, 1872-1941, President of Baugh and Sons, 1932 (Includes signature), 4 (Box 1)
    - Potato field, 1911 Almanac, 9A (Box 1)
    - Ship at dock, 1908 Almanac, 38-A (Box 1)
    - Norfolk, Va., Office, 49-A-1 (Box 1)
    - Machinery (Ovens), 54-A (Box 1)
    - Bag of phosphate, 108-A (Box 1)
    - Potato field with men and equipment, 1911, 125-A (Box 1)
    - Shelf display of Baugh products, including view of Delaware River Chemical Works, circa 1905, 126-A-2 (Box 1)
    - Bone shed and workers at a Baugh & Sons plant, 129-A (Box 1)
    - Cornfield and farm buildings, Hackensack, N.J., 155 (Box 1)
    - Farm workers and outbuildings, Hackensack, N.J., 157 (Box 1)
    - Cornfield with farmer and equipment, 164 (Box 1)
    - Cornfield and equipment, 170 (Box 1)
    - Cornfield on James Wharton Farm, Newtown Square, Pa., 1910, 175 (Box 1)
    - Potato field, Garrison Farm, Bridgeton, 1910, 176 (Box 1)
    - Potato field, Mich Farm, 1910, 180 (Box 1)
    - Potato field, Mich Bros., 1910, 186 (Box 1)
    - Mat for 1914 raw bone manures ad, 207 (Box 1)
    - Mat for Supplemental to Baugh's Booklet, 218 (Box 1)
    - Potato field, farm buildings in background, 453-A (Box 1)
    - Hay field with men, 456 (Box 1)
    - Hay field with men, 458-B (Box 1)
    - Hay field with men (similar to 456), 459 (Box 1)
    - Hay field with men and equipment, 463 (Box 1)
    - Potato field with men, 1911, 481 (Box 1)
    - Potato field, 1911, 482 (Box 1)
    - Potato field, 1911, 484 (Box 1)
    - Potato field, 485 (Box 1)
    - Office and desk at Baugh & Sons, Jan., 1905, 561B (Box 1)
    - Mr. C. Howard Ward's house, 612-A (Box 1)
    - Mr. C. Howard Ward's house, 612-B (Box 1)
    - Family on porch of house, 637 (Box 1)
    - Bag of Baugh's 12 & 5 phosphate and potash, 698 (Box 1)
    - Office of J. Watson Craft (dealer in lumber, coal, flour, fertilizer, grain and feed), with personnel in front, Amblen Pa., 1913, 776 (Box 1)
    - Mat for 1911 raw bone manures ad, 810 (Box 1)
    - Burton's Point, docks and building, 838 (Box 1)
    - 3-A Crop field with men and Baugh & Sons sign, 865
      - Empty bags of Baugh & Sons products displayed, 1911 Almanac, 94 (Box 1)
      - Street scene, town unknown, with store of Charles A. Long, dealer in fertilizer, etc., 292-A (Box 1)
    - Dried cornstalk, 886 (Box 1)
    - Mat for Baugh's Farmers' 1911 Almanac, 890 (Box 1)
    - Potato field with farmer and equipment, 924 (Box 1)
    - Potato field with farmer and horse, 931 (Box 1)
    - Fire at Union Petroleum Oil Work, 1913, 949 (Box 1)
    - Potato field with workers during harvesting, and wagon, 1914 Almanac, 976 (Box 1)
    - Cornfield with man and boy, 1914 Almanac, 988 (Box 1)
    - Baugh & Sons display and personnel, probably at a fair, 996 (Box 1)
    - Baugh & Sons exhibit at New York State Fruit Growers Assoc., Rochester, N.Y., 1914, 1023 (Box 1)
    - Bone shed and workers at a Baugh & Sons plant, 1041 (Box 1)
    - Potato field, Minch Berry Farm, 1913, 1071 (Box 1)
    - Tobacco field and farm buildings, 1107 (Box 1)
    - Tobacco field of Mr. Jacoby, 1108 (Box 1)
    - Family on porch of house, 1126 (Box 1)
    - Cornfield with men, 1914, 1135 (Box 1)
    - Man and woman in field, 1161 (Box 1)
    - Tobacco field of C. E. Hart, Ayden, N.C., 1914, 1167 (Box 1)
    - Wm. Wright on farm of Alex C. Ferguson, Burlington, N.J., 1922, 1600 (Box 1)
    - Field of ensilage corn, Ephraim T. Gill farm, Haddonfield, N.J., 1922, 1638 (Box 1)
    - A portion of a herd of 175 Ayrshire cattle, Mrs. John R. Valentine's Highland Farm, Bryn Mawr, Pa., 1922, 1659 (Box 1)
    - A scene around the stables, Highland Farm, 1922, 1661 (Box 1)
    - Avenue of French poplar trees, Highland Farm, 1922, 1663 (Box 1)
    - A famous hunter (horse) and his keeper, Highland Farm, 1922, 1665 (Box 1)
    - Potato field and men, Joseph M. Garrison's farm, Elmer, N.J., 1922, 1685 (Box 1)
    - Cotton plant, 1922, 1691 (Box 1)
    - Alvarez y Rodriguez display, 1823 (Box 1)
    - North Carolina cotton crop of W.E. Askew, 1914 and 1923 Almanacs, 1826 (Box 1)
    - Cornfield and man, U.H. McCarter's Tower Hill Farm, Red Bank, N.J., 1923, 1885 (Box 1)
    - Harvesting in Potato field of Minch Bros., 1911, 1896 (Box 1)
    - Farm produce stand of Fra. Carhart, Hazlet, Keyport, N.J., 1923. Dealer and farmer., 1908 (Box 1)
    - Cornfield and people, 1924, 1943 (Box 1)
    - Cornfield of George Stillwell, Hopewell, N.J., 1925, 2016 (Box 1)
    - Cornfield of George Stillwell with man in scene, 1925, Hopewell, N.J., 2017 (Box 1)
  - Unnumbered Photographs
    - Baugh & Sons Co. and Baugh Chemical Co. offices in Seaboard Bank Bldg., Norfolk, Va. (Box 1)
    - Baugh & Sons Co. and Baugh Chemical Co. offices in building (Box 1)
    - E.T. Short, English Tailor & Importer, New York, store and personnel (Box 1)
    - Plant machinery (Box 1)
    - Bone shed (2) (Box 1)
    - Fertilizer bags (2) (Box 1)
    - Baugh & Sons plant, hay wagon, and trade mark, 1913 Almanac (Box 1)
    - Mat for bone meal bag ad (Box 1)
    - Mat for four fertilizer bags for ad (Box 1)
    - George S. Snyder residence (Box 1)
    - Ship at dock unloading bones (2) (Box 1)
    - Plant scene - bone processing (Box 1)
- Oversize Photographs, 1912-1923 and undated, (2 folders)
  - Potato field including buildings, men, and equipment, 871 (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - Four pictures at least one of which was in 1912 Almanac (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - E. H. Keen & Co., flour, feed, and grain dealer, 876 (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - Town scene with flags and bunting on buildings, 386 (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - C. Frank Williamson business, 390 (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - Philips-Thompson Co.'s Christina Mills and Grain Elevator. Old streetcar also in scene. 1912 Almanac., 393 (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - Ship Erhard at dock, 1913, 1015 (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - Baugh's plant at dockside, Baltimore. 1922 Almanac., 1575 (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - Mat for picture of fertilizer bag. 1923 Almanac., 1833-A (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - Three plant and dockside scenes Nos. 101-A (1912) Almanac), 91-A, 330-A (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - Man with bags of various Baugh fertilizer products (Box Sec. A OV5)
  - George S. Snyder residence and warehouse, Nos. 344-A, 346-A (1912 Almanac). Includes 389-A, unidentified dealer's establishment, and inset of Delaware River Chemical Works (Box Sec. A OV5)